Contact

7877106357 (Mobile) vianessegonzalez@hotmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/vianessegonzalez (LinkedIn) vianesse.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Core Java
Data Analytics
PostgreSQL

Certifications

USF Coding Bootcamp Certificate

Honors-Awards

AON Impact Award
AON Star Award
Service Star
Academic Excellence
AON Innovation Award

Vianesse Gonzalez

Data Analyst at Aon

Greater Tampa Bay Area

Summary

Experienced Data Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the financial and health insurance services industry. Skilled in data science, data mining, SQL, Access, Excel (Power Pivot), VBA, Alteryx, Power BI and advanced Dashboards. Certified with technical expertise and coding skills needed to work as a full stack software consultant with knowledge of the latest in-demand enterprise IT technologies, software requirements in an Agile environment and coding practices. Intermediate in: Core Java, Java Script, SQL, HTML.

Experience

Aon
Data Analyst
October 2017 - Present (3 years 8 months)
Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

Qinetix Group, LLC
Data Analyst
February 2014 - May 2016 (2 years 4 months)

Developed database objects, including tables, views and materialized views using SQL. Development and implementation of health insurance reports, prepared administrative claims analysis reports for small and large groups. Developed and implemented projection reports for all groups. Ability to formulate, gather, analyze and present complex health care, informational and statistical data to reach valid conclusions. Identified and documented detailed business rules and use cases based on requirements analysis. Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs. Built library of models and reusable knowledge-base assets to produce consistent and streamlined business intelligence results. Synthesized current business intelligence data to produce reports and polished presentations highlighting findings and recommending changes

Triple-S Underwriter July 2000 - March 2011 (10 years 9 months)

Created and prepared Financial Reports for the Company's Executives.

Performed system analysis, documentation, testing, implementation and user support for platform transitions: Excel to Step Wise and Excel to web based. In charge of the maintenance and changes of the Step Wise Software used to determine the renewal and quotes for all groups. Offer administrative support to the manager preparing internal presentations, in the development of new projects and special reports, and giving technical support to other divisions. Saved \$1.5M to a client by researching and implementing a platform/ programming that calculated the possible savings for the client if the used a specific health program (Retiree Subsidy Center of the Company clients subscribed in CMS)

Education

Universidad de Puerto Rico

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics and Computer Science · (1996 - 2000)